Guide to the YMCA - Student Division Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Addendum - 2010, 1910-1956; Series VII
  - Student work during World War II
    - Report re. USO Grant-In-Aid, 1943 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - National Intercollegiate Christian Council
    - Correspondence and minutes: wartime activities, 1942-1943 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Christian Social Reconstruction Committee, 1942-1943 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - National Commission on Ethnic Minorities, 1939-1941 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Commission on the World Christian Mission, 1935-1943 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Subcommittee on the University Christian Mission, 1938-1941 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Economics Commission, 1937-1941 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Peace Commission, 1933-1945 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Planning Committee, 1936-1943 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Committee on Relations with the Churches, 1939 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Program Commission / Council / Committee, 1936-1944 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Preparatory materials for NICC meetings, 1938-1940 (Box 89, Folder 5-6)
    - "Actions of the NICC", 1936-1942 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - "Campus and Church" bulletin, 1940-1944 (Box 89, Folder 8-9)
    - Reports, 1940s (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Publication sale records, 1941 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Other organizations
    - National Commission on University Work of the Council of Church Boards of Education, 1942-1943 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - World Student Christian Federation: Report for Conference Concerning Relationships (n.d.); Report from USA to the Pacific Area Conferenc eof the WSCF (1936); Communion liturgy (1956), 1936,1956, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - YMCA National Council and World Convention: Resolution on Intercultural and Interracial Relations adopted at conference in Cleveland, 1931 Aug (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - YMCA National Council: radio script "Youth on the March", 1937 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Committee on Student Rehabilitation Project Under the World Youth Fund, 1947 (Box 90, Folder 18)
  - History of Student YMCA
    - Typescript drafts of history of the Student YMCA by Robert Weidensall (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Notebook of Robert Weidensall, 1910 (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - Typescript documents and articles regarding college life and YMCA (Box 90, Folder 21)
- Addendum - 2013, Series VIII
  - Interseminary Movement
    - Conference of Professors and Students
      - Syllabus, notes of Paul Micou (Secretary for Theological Seminaries, International Committee of YMCAs), and resolutions from Conferences of Professors and Students of Theological Seminaries, Nov 20-21, 1911 (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Minutes, delegate roster, and program from Conference of Professors and Students of Theological Seminaries of the Eastern Part of the United States, Drew Theological Seminary, Madison, NJ, Feb 27-March 1, 1915 (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - Reports, correspondence of P. Micou, and program from Conference of Professors and Students of Theological Seminaries of the West and Southwest of the United States, Louisville, KY, December 3-5, 1915 (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Delegate list, program, and reports from Conference of Professors and Students of Theological Seminaries of the Eastern Part of the United States, Auburn Theological Seminary, Auburn, NY, Feb 9-11, 1917 (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - Program, registration blank, minutes and report from Conference of Professors and Students of Theological Seminaries of the Eastern Part of the United States, Yale, April 6-8, 1923 (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - Delegate list, suggested program for Theological Students and Professors, Detroit, MI, December 31, 1930-January 1, 1931 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence between R. P. Wilder and H. P. Anderson re. Theological Seminary work, 1898-1899, 1937 (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - Minutes, correspondence of P. Micou, and program from Fourth Annual Conference of Students of the Colleges and Universities of New York State at Auburn Seminary, March 18-19, 1916 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Eastern College Men
      - Delegate list, program, and newspaper clipping from the Twelfth Annual Conference of Eastern College Men on the Christian Ministry, Andover Theological Seminary, Cambridge, MA, March 24-26, 1916 (Box 91, Folder 9)
      - Notes and delegate list from the Thirteenth Annual Conference of Eastern College Men on the Christian Ministry, Union Theological Seminary, March 16-18, 1917 (Box 91, Folder 10)
      - Memo and program re. Fourteenth Annual Conference of Eastern College Men, Hartford Theological Seminary, March 19-21, 1920 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Interseminary
      - Various brochures, minutes, reports re. Interseminary movement. Some reports written by H. P. Andersen, secretary of NC YMCA region, 1902-1943 (Box 91, Folder 12)
      - Interseminary Conference documents include constitutions, correspondence, programs, etc., 1925-1934 (Box 91, Folder 13)
      - Interseminary conferences divided by regions, 1927-1943 (Box 91, Folder 14)
      - Ohio Inter-Seminary Student Conference meeting at Oberlin, Ohio, April 25-28, 1928 (Box 92, Folder 15)
      - The Interseminarian: a news bulletin of the Interseminary movement in the United States (newsletter/periodical), 1929-1946 and list of important headmasters and masters in the New England field. (Box 92, Folder 16)
      - Interseminary mailing lists, 1933-34 (Box 92, Folder 17)
      - Report of the work of the Interseminary movement, 1940: A brief history of the Interseminary Movement Appendix A 1943; A final report to the National Interseminary Movement Committee, 1944., 1940-1944 (Box 92, Folder 18)
      - Examination of Statement of Purpose of Interseminary Movement, 1941 (Box 92, Folder 19)
      - Southeastern Interseminary conference, correspondence of Cyrus Pangborn, schedules, reports, 1942-1943 (Box 92, Folder 20)
      - A brief history of the Interseminary Movement prepared by William Richey Hogg, January 15, 1945 (Box 92, Folder 21)
    - Milwaukee Clippings
      - Address of Dr. Robert E. Spear at Student's Seminary Conference, Indianapolis, Indiana, Dec 27, 1923 (Box 92, Folder 22)
      - Scrapbook labeled, "Toward a New Economic Society" press clippings, April-July 1931 (Box 92, Folder 23)
      - Proceedings of the Seminary Student Conference, Hotel Severn, Indianapolis (2 copies), Dec. 27, 1923 (Box 92, Folder 24)
      - Binder/scrapbook labeled National Student Conference Book I MIlwaukee Clippings, etc, 1926-1927 (Box 92, Folder 25)
      - Binder/scrapbook labeled National Student Conference Book I MIlwaukee Clippings, etc (cont'd), 1926-1927 (Box 93, Folder 26 (cont'd))
      - Binder/scrapbook labeled Milwaukee Conference press clippings, Book II, 1926-1927 (Box 93, Folder 27)
      - Binder/scrapbook labeled Milwaukee Conference press clippings, Book II (cont'd), 1926-27 (Box 93, Folder 28 (cont'd))
    - Miscellaneous Conferences
      - Programs from West Coast Conferences: A Conference Relating to Church Leadership, San Anselmo, CA, January 26-27, 1912; Presentation & Discussion of Christian Life Work opportunities, Univ of Washington, Feb 11-13, 1916; MInistry-Missions Conference: A Consideration of the World Wide Call for Christian Leaders, Oregon Agriculture College, Feb 18-20, 1916; College and Theological Students Conference: World Conditions and the Christian Church, "On the Quad," Stanford University, Jan 28-29, 1916, 1912-1916 (Box 93, Folder 29)
      - Delegate list and program from Fifth Annual Conference of the Colleges and Universities of New York State concerning the Christian Ministry held at Rochester Theological Seminary, March 17-18, 1917 (Box 93, Folder 30)
      - Programs from Christian Leadership and Training Conference Occidental College, LA, April 13-15, 1917; First Life and Note Conference subject "The Christian Ministry", University of Colorado, March 23, 1917; Life Work Conference on "The Christian Ministry", University of Denver, April 20, 1917; Inter-Seminary Dinner and Conference, San Francisco, CA, March 2, 1917; Program and findings and resolutions from Ministry-Missions Conference, Willamette University, April 6-8, 1917, March-April 1917 (Box 93, Folder 31)
      - Miscellaneous Conference Programs, 1924 (Box 93, Folder 32)
    - National Conference of Theological Students
      - Delegate list, program, resolutions and report from National Conference of Theological Students: The Personal Qualifications of a Minister in the Modern Community, Milwaukee, WI, December 27-28, 1926 (Box 93, Folder 33)
      - Delegate list, correspondence, program and report from National Conference of Theological Students: Toward a More United Church, Detroit, MI, Dec 27-28, 1927 (Box 93, Folder 34)
      - Delegate list, informational materials, and informal notes of David R. Porter re. National Conference of Theological Students and Professors, Dec 1931 (Box 93, Folder 35)
      - National Conference of Theological Students, program, roster, income, and expenditures, correspondence, and printed material Dec 27, 1935 (Box 94, Folder 36)
      - Seventh National Conference for Theological Students includes program, correspondence, reports, Miami University, Oxford, OH, December 27, 1941-Jan 3, 1942. Sixth National Theological Conference: The Theological Section of the National Student Assembly includes program, brochure, agenda, roster, correspondence, minutes, Dec 27, 1937-Jan 1, 1938. Fifth National Conference of Theological Students, Indianapolis, program, brochures, news release, roster, Dec 27-28, 1935. Fourth National Conference for Theological Students, Buffalo, NY, brochure, Dec 20, 1931-Jan 3, 1932. Pamphlet - Theological Students and the Christian Association Movement by David R. Porter, 1926. Brochures for National Conference of Theological Students 1926 and 1927, 1926-1942 (Box 94, Folder 37)
      - Report and roster of Sixth National Student Assembly Theological Section, Dec 27, 1937- Jan 1, 1938 (Box 94, Folder 38)
      - Report of the Seventh National Conference for Theological Students, Dec 27, 1941-Jan 3, 1942 (Box 94, Folder 39)
  - World's Student Christian Federation
    - Day of Prayer
      - World's Student Christian Federation Day of Prayer materials, 1912-1943 (Box 94, Folder 40)
      - WSCF Day of Prayer materials, 1936-1940 (Box 94, Folder 41)
      - WSCF Day of Prayer materials, 1941-1954 (Box 94, Folder 42)
    - Executive Committee
      - Minutes of the first two meetings of World's Student Christian Federation Executive Committee includes group photograph from later meeting, August 6, 1920, June 2-7, 1921 (Box 94, Folder 43)
      - Minutes of WSCF Executive Committee, May 19-26, 1923 (Box 94, Folder 44)
      - Minutes and documents of WSCF Executive Committee, May 6-12, 1925. Minutes of the Joint Conference of the Word's YMCA; YMCA and WSCF, May 3-5, 1925, May 1925 (Box 94, Folder 45)
      - Minutes of WSCF Executive Committee, June 4-9, 1927 (Box 94, Folder 46)
      - Minutes of WSCF Executive Committee, August 7-14, 1930 (Box 94, Folder 47)
      - Minutes of WSCF Executive Committee and reports presented, Nominations to General Committee from US Delegation (General Committee postponed until 1932), July 14-20, 1931 (Box 94, Folder 48)
      - Minutes of the WSCF Executive Committee meeting, August 10-14, 1934 (Box 94, Folder 49)
      - Minutes of the Executive Committee, July 30-August 1, 1937 (Box 94, Folder 50)
      - Minutes of the Executive Committee, July 30-August 1, 1939 (Box 95, Folder 51)
      - Agenda for WSCF Executive Committee, July 12-14, 1947 (Box 95, Folder 52)
      - Minutes of WSCF Executive Committee meeting, August 6-10, 1950 (Box 95, Folder 53)
      - Minutes of WSCF Executive Committee meeting, August 1951 (Box 95, Folder 54)
      - Minutes of WSCF Executive meeting, April 18-22, 1952 (Box 95, Folder 55)
      - WSCF Executive Committee meeting at Monmouth College, IL, August 1-6, 1954 (Box 95, Folder 56)
      - Report on WSCF Executive Committee by Paul E. Schrading, August 12-19, 1955 (Box 95, Folder 57)
    - Executive and General Committee
      - Minutes and documents of World's Student Christian Federation Executive and General Committee includes group photograph of participants, August 6-21, 1924 (Box 95, Folder 58)
      - Minutes and documents of WSCF Executive and General Committee including WSCF 3 year report, August 11-25, 1926 (Box 95, Folder 59)
      - Minutes and other documents from WSCF General Committee and Executive Committee meeting including photograph of American delegation, Mysore, India, Dec 5-16, 1928 (Box 95, Folder 60)
    - General Committee
      - Minutes of World's Student Christian Federation General Committee, May 26-31, 1913 (Box 95, Folder 61)
      - Minutes and documents of WSCF General Committee including October 1920 issue of the Student World, November 1920 issue of The Australasian Intercollegian, and correspondence of David R. Porter, July 30-August 7, 1920, July-November 1920 (Box 95, Folder 62)
      - Minutes and documents of WSCF General Committee including report by David R. Porter, March 29-April 2, April 11-12, 1922 (Box 95, Folder 63)
      - WSCF Executive Committee meeting and Retreat of Student Christian Movement (SCM) Leaders of 16 nations, includes correspondence of David R. Porter who seems to have been planning a meeting, Williams College, MA, July 5-12, 1931 (Box 96, Folder 64)
      - General Committee documents, Zeist, Holland, August 13-23, 1932 (Box 96, Folder 65)
      - General Committee documents, Zeist, Holland (cont'd), August 13-23, 1932 (Box 96, Folder 66 (cont'd))
      - Minutes and documents of the WSCF General Committee, Chamcoria, Bulgaria, August 5-15, 1935 (Box 96, Folder 67)
      - Minutes and documents from WSCF General Committee meeting, Bievres, France, August 8-18, 1938 (Box 96, Folder 68)
      - WSCF Conference, NYC, May incl. minutes of the WSCF General Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 96, Folder 69)
      - Minutes of the WSCF General Committee, reports to General Committee, correspondence to R. H. Edwin Espy re. delegates to conference, circulars re. general committee meeting, August 9-20, 1946 (Box 96, Folder 70)
      - WSCF General Committee - United Student Christian Council docs, Inter-Communion and the Student YMCA, Report to the WSCF from National Student YMCA, USA 1946-1949, Whitby, Canada, Aug 9-21, 1949 (Box 97, Folder 71)
      - Poll of National Student Council Members re. nomination of Kenneth B. Smith as student rep to WSCF General Committee meeting in Poona, Indiana, 1953 (Box 97, Folder 72)
    - Leader's Meeting
      - World's Student Christian Federation Leader's Meeting, Poughkeepsie, NY, Dec 16-18, 1940 (Box 97, Folder 73)
      - Memo re. Committee meeting to plan WSCF Leader's Meeting, March 5, 1945 (Box 97, Folder 74)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Bulletin re. World's Student Christian Federation (WSCF) International Study Conference for Workers Among Boys and Girls in Secondary schools, February 14, 1936 (Box 97, Folder 75)
      - Circular letter re. WSCF International Summer Conference for Men and Women Students, Les Avants, August 5-11, 1936 (Box 97, Folder 76)
      - Circular letters re. WSCF Mountain Camp Conference, August 20-30, 1938 (Box 97, Folder 77)
      - Committee on Cooperation in WSCF, reports, constitution, 3 year reports of WSCF and directory, 1936-1940 (Box 97, Folder 78)
      - Correspondence re. Ruth Rouse's WSCF History Project incl. Ruth Rouse, Roland Elliot, and David Porter, 1940 (Box 97, Folder 79)
      - Correspondence re. WSCF Nunspeet Conference, February-April 1939 (Box 97, Folder 80)
      - Delegate list and morning prayer service for WSCF Lundsberg Conference, Aug 1-9, 1947 (Box 97, Folder 81)
      - Delegate nominations, agenda, notes from WSCF American-European Commission Retreat, June 19-23, 1931 (Box 97, Folder 82)
      - Easter weekend WSCF Conference at Vassar, December 1942-April 1943 (Box 97, Folder 83)
      - Federation meeting invitation in NYC, September 30, 1943 (Box 97, Folder 84)
      - Minutes and reports (includes handwritten report of Luther Tucker) of the WSCF Java Conference, September 6-14, 1933 (Box 97, Folder 85)
      - Minutes of the WSCF meeting of the council of secretaries of South Eastern European student Christian movements, Belgrade, February 17-20, 1940 (Box 97, Folder 86)
      - Minutes of WSCF Student Friendship Fund, 1922-1927 (Box 97, Folder 87)
      - Miscellaneous WSCF document re. Conferences including correspondence of A. Roland Elliot and David R. Porter, 1929-1937 (Box 98, Folder 88)
      - More questions for thinking ahead: A message from a group of students, meeting at Presinge, near Geneva, September 2-4, 1942 (Box 98, Folder 89)
      - Preparatory material for WSCF Consultative meeting, April 1944 (Box 98, Folder 90)
      - Proposed Agenda WSCF University Conference, July 4-10, 1947 (Box 98, Folder 91)
      - Reports from WSCF Conference of Secondary School Workers, July 1932 (Box 98, Folder 92)
      - Rough notes on the informal meeting of WSCF, JUly 17-18, 1943 (Box 98, Folder 93)
      - WSCF Consultative meeting, Poughkeepsie, NY, Feb 1942 (Box 98, Folder 94)
      - WSCF reports and papers, List of delegates attending WSCF conferences 1898-1928, List of delegates attending International Student Service (ISS) conferences 1921-1930, 3 year report, 1921-1946, 1898-1928; 1921-1930; 1921-1946 (Box 98, Folder 95)
  - Student Volunteer Movement
    - Student Volunteer Movement Quadrennial, delegate list, printed materials, reports, Des Moines, Dec 31, 1919-Jan 4, 1920 (Box 98, Folder 96)
    - David Porter's SVM Quad file, delegate list, minutes, reports, SVM hymnal, Indianapolis, 1923-1924 (Box 98, Folder 97)
    - A. R. Elliot's planning files re. SVM Quadrennial in Detroit, MI, correspondence, delegate lists, minutes, brochures, etc, 1927-1928 (Box 98, Folder 98)
    - David Porter's SVM Quad file, delegate list, brochures program, Buffalo, NY, December 31, 1931-January 1, 1932 (Box 99, Folder 99)
    - A. R. Elliot's planning files on SVM Quadrennial in Indianapolis, includes brochures, minutes, poster, notes, correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 99, Folder 100)
    - A. R. Elliot's planning files re. SVM Quadrennial in Toronto included minutes, programs, brochures, correspondence, 1939 (Box 99, Folder 101)
    - Student Volunteer Movement Quadrennial at Wooster College: Planning committee for the student planning conference on the World Mission for the Church includes correspondence, minutes, brochures, etc; files of A. R. Elliot, April 1942-January 1944 (Box 99, Folder 102)
    - Student Volunteer Movement Quadrennial at Wooster College: Planning committee for the student planning conference on the World Mission for the Church includes correspondence, minutes, brochures, etc; files of A. R. Elliot (cont'd), April 1942-January 1944 (Box 99, Folder 103 (con'td))
    - Report re. National Student Winter Conference in China, March-April 1945 (Box 99, Folder 104)
  - Other Organizations
    - Agenda and reports from the International Confederation of Studies, Paris, France, 1928 (Box 99, Folder 105)
    - British Student Christian Movement: Reports of Tissington Tatlow (General Secretary of the British SCM ) upon his visit in North American field of student work, Tatlow's itineraries, correspondence, 1912-1913, 1915 (Box 99, Folder 106)
    - British SCM: Minutes of the General Council of British SCM, December 18-20, 1940 (Box 100, Folder 107)
    - British SCM: Extract of minutes of General Council of British SCM, March 31-April 3, 1944 (Box 100, Folder 108)
    - British Student Volunteer Movement: Memo re. groups for discussion at British SVM Quadrennial, January 1929 (Box 100, Folder 109)
    - British SVM: Possible delegate list to British SVM Quadrennial, November 1936 (Box 100, Folder 110)
    - Correspondence, delegate list, directory, and Federal Council Bulletin re. World Conference on Life and Work at Oxford, July 12-26, 1937 (Box 100, Folder 111)
    - Reports and correspondence of David R. Porter re. Anglo-American Conference, 1928-1931 (Box 100, Folder 112)
    - Training for Ministry in Wartime pamphlet, draft, memos to Cyrus Pangborn, 1943 (Box 100, Folder 113)
    - Young Men's Christian Association: Minutes of the Executive Committee of Life Work Recruiting Conference incl. correspondence of Paul MIcou, 1914 (Box 100, Folder 114)
    - YMCA: Theological Sub-committee of the National Council of the YMCA minutes, 1916, 1922-1927, 1932 (Box 100, Folder 115)
    - YMCA: Pacific Area Conferences minutes and documents including correspondence, 1925, 1928, 1931, 1936 (Box 100, Folder 116)
    - YMCA: Pacific Area Conferences minutes and documents including correspondence (cont'd), 1925, 1928, 1931, 1936 (Box 100, Folder 117)
    - YMCA: Address to National Advisory Council of National Student Council of YMCA, "Luther Wishard and the Birth of the Intercollegiate YMCA" by David B. Lowry, Princeton, 1951 (Box 100, Folder 118)